In this next clip we're going to talk about wind chill and wind chill factors.
This is a critical consideration when you're dealing with the outdoors.
The wind chill and your dress.
You dress for wind chill, not for the temperature that you have outside.
For instance right here, since we been filming here for this clip, a cloud came over and the temperature dropped ten degrees just in the last two minutes.
And the wind chill actually adds extra to that temperature drop.
So wind chill, we'll take a look at this wind chill chart and I'll show you what kind of temperature drops you have even for a minor change in the wind.
On this wind chill chart you have the temperature across the top, and then you have the wind speed along the sides.
And then you just cross reference your data and you'll come up with the actual real temperature, real life temperature that you have to dress for.
A five degree shift in the wind will drop the actual real life temperature ten to fifteen degrees.
This wind chill chart is available from the NOA weather and the National Weather Service as a free download from their website.